gosquared.com 2014-10-11

# Privacy - Legal - GoSquared

## Who we are

Put simply, GoSquared Ltd (" **GoSquared** ", " **us** " or " **we** ") provides real-time web analytics services. Web analytics is about more than just tables and charts. It's about helping improve websites. We are registered on the UK Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) register with registration number Z2561177. Our registered company number is 5696757, and our registered address is 3 Barn Hawe, High Street, Edenbridge, Kent, England, TN8 5AQ.

We have developed this Privacy Policy to explain generally how we collect and use information. It is relevant to our customers and people that use our website. It is supplemented by the GoSquared Analytics Service: Statement on Protecting Your Data – that statement is helpful for people that want to know about how our analytics service operates (such as our customers and those that use our customers' websites).

## What is in our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy covers the collection and use of personal information such as names, contact details and payment details (" **Personal Information** ") that may be collected by us about you as a result of you interacting with us or any webpage created, owned or maintained by us, such as www.gosquared.com (the " **Websites** "). Interacting with GoSquared includes (but is not limited to): visiting any of our Websites, purchasing from any of our Websites, or contacting or interacting with our sales or support staff.

Please take a moment to read this Privacy Policy to learn more about our information practices, including what type of information is gathered, how and for what purposes the information is used for, to whom we disclose the information to, and how we safeguard your Personal Information.

 **By using our Websites, products or services, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your Personal Information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with the terms of this Privacy Policy please do not register for or use the GoSquared Websites (including www.gosquared.com) or any service provided by us.**

Please feel free to email us at [support@gosquared.com](mailto:support@gosquared.com) at any time if you have any questions about GoSquared's policies and practices.

## Your privacy

Your privacy is a priority at GoSquared and we go to great lengths to protect it. We will not pass on your personal details to any third party (unless we are required to by law and as detailed in section 'When we will disclose your Personal Information), nor will we sell or rent your personally identifiable information or a list of our customers to third parties. However, in order for us to offer our services to our users; to enhance the quality of its service from time to time; and to protect the interests of our users, we will in limited circumstances and as further described in this policy, share some of your information with third parties under strict restrictions.

## Why we collect Personal Information

We collect your Personal Information for the purpose of providing you with (and administering) the use of our Websites, products and/or services, whether we do so for payment or free of charge. Your Personal Information also enables us to respond to specific requests that you have made, and to improve the way that we operate and what we offer.

In addition, your Personal Information helps us contact you and keep you updated on any announcements that we think are relevant to you. The ways in which we may use your information for marketing announcements are explained below under "marketing preferences".

Announcements include product and service updates, news and announcements about GoSquared and its partners. Announcements may also be alerts and notifications sent to you as part of the service we provide when alerting you about events concerning your website.

## What Personal Information we collect

 **When you register on our Websites**

Upon registration with GoSquared for a user account you are required to provide the following information: your first and last name, email address and a secure password that only you know. You may optionally provide, or be required to provide, other types of Personal Information at a later date in the GoSquared User Account area (see below).

 **When you use our products and services**

Some of our products and services require financial details to facilitate payment and/or registration for these products and services. Financial information comprises of Credit or Debit Card details or, if the customer opts for payment via PayPal, the necessary information PayPal requires for processing the transaction. For payments via PayPal, the information PayPal requires from you is beyond our control and conducted within PayPal's website and jurisdiction and is therefore subject to their privacy policy and terms of use.

All financial and otherwise sensitive information will only be collected in a secure environment in which we have taken the thorough precautions and vigilance necessary to process such information. This information will only ever be transferred over an industry standard encrypted connection using SSL/TLS encryption technology directly to the secure and reputable payments partner we use to validate, manage and process Credit and Debit Card transactions. Our payments partner is fully PCI-DSS certified and has passed a myriad of security audits to assure data integrity and security. Some user information is shared with the payments partner, including email address, first name, last name, company name, VAT number and billing information for the purpose of invoicing, refunds, reporting, management and administration. We record and retain information about all transactions that take place for use in our own bookkeeping and reports, as well as for providing customer support, supporting refunds and promotions, and preventing fraud.

If you use any of our products or services we will often need to know your full name, home address, phone number, email address and contact preferences so that we can process your order and provide you with the best possible service, personalisation and support. Information about the GoSquared products or services that you subscribe for, such as the date of purchase and information relating to a support or service issues, may also be collected by us in connection with administering our operations.

 **Registering websites for our analytics service**

In addition to the Personal Information required to register an account, we require further information pertaining to any website you register for the GoSquared analytics service. At a minimum, this will include your website name and website domain. You may only provide this information about websites you directly own, or for websites you have express permission from the rightful owners to act on behalf of. GoSquared reserves the right to refuse or later terminate service without warning to any user breaching this rule.

 **Information collected through our analytics service**

Our products and services include data tracking and processing facilities using data you have given us permission to collect by signing up for an account with us. Analytical data about your website and its traffic, including but not limited to volume (total number of hits, number of unique visitors, number of returning visitors, number of new visitors, number of pages browsed per view) sources (where your traffic is coming from), your website's content (website pages, source code, applications, interface), referrers (internal, external and search engine), search engine throughput (queries, keywords), robots, visitor parameters (browsers, platforms, language, screen resolutions, Geographic Location, IP addresses, custom identifiers) and visitor behaviour (i.e. what pages were visited and in what order) is collected, processed and stored on our servers and replicated across secure redundant data stores. Our systems also access and interact with your websites, servers and applications for the purposes of snapshotting your websites' appearance, verifying accessibility of functional, active content and scanning for the existence of the GoSquared Tracking Code. This is by no means an exhaustive list of data we collect, and the volume and variety of data we collect is subject to frequent change and expansion as we develop and maintain our systems. We will also occasionally use all or any subset of the data we collect about your website and its traffic to test and monitor any parts of our system that are in production or development. The data we collect about your website and its traffic are also vulnerable to interruption, corruption, inaccuracy, degradation, loss and deletion as a result of accidental factors (such as system failure) or deliberate factors (such as violation of our Terms of Service). As such, we cannot guarantee your data will always remain accurate, accessible, or available. Further information on our analytics service data is set out in the GoSquared Analytics Service: Statement on Protecting Your Data

 **The GoSquared Affiliate Program**

In order to receive payment from the GoSquared Affiliate Program, it is necessary for us to take your bank details plus any other information which we deem necessary to pay you under the GoSquared Affiliate Program. Such information will be strongly encrypted and will never stay on our servers for a period longer than necessary to process such payments (usually no more than a month). GoSquared does everything possible to prevent disclosure of such information to unauthorised persons and such information is used strictly for the purpose of payment alone. We treat the safety and security of every user's financial information as a top priority. GoSquared never shares the financial information of its users with anyone other than where required by payment processors and fraud prevention agencies.

## Marketing preferences

All our marketing emails are optional. If you do not want GoSquared to keep you up to date with our news and the latest information on products and services, you can opt-out of email communications using the unsubscribe facility provided at the bottom of each email correspondence.

Please note that even if you have unsubscribed, emails which have direct correlation with your personal use of our products and services, including but not limited to notifications about your account, payments, activations, confirmations, receipts, payment enquiries, password reminders, replies to correspondence from you, urgent communications and vital updates from GoSquared's staff, will continue to be received. If any of these emails are received then please acknowledge that they would have been sent on an individual basis and that your attention is required on the corresponding matter.

 **Enquiries about marketing preferences**

Any enquires about GoSquared should be directed to: [support@gosquared.com](mailto:support@gosquared.com). This email address should also be used for updating customer information in the event that certain pages are down or are temporarily unavailable to you. If you would like help with anything, you may also use our support pages.

## When will we disclose your Personal Information

GoSquared takes your privacy very seriously. Be assured that we do not sell or rent your contact information to other marketers. To help us provide superior service, your Personal Information may be shared with legal entities within GoSquared's group globally who will safeguard it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. There are also times when it may be advantageous for GoSquared to make certain Personal Information about you available to companies that GoSquared has a strategic relationship with or that perform work for GoSquared to provide products and services to you on our behalf. These companies may help us process information, extend credit, fulfil customer orders, deliver our products and services to you, store or manage or enhance data, provide customer service, assess your interest in our products and services, or conduct customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are also obligated to protect your Personal Information in accordance with GoSquared's policies. Without such information being made available, it would be difficult for you to purchase our products and services, have our products and services delivered to you, receive customer service, provide us feedback to improve our products and services, or access certain offers and content on our Websites.

As GoSquared operates its Websites and its products and services globally, we may transfer your data to other countries, including countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA) such as the United States of America. However, in all circumstances, we will take steps to ensure that your Personal Information receives the same level of protection as within the EEA, that it is kept secure and used only in accordance with our instructions and for the purposes explained in this Privacy Policy.

At times we may be required by law or litigation to disclose your Personal Information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary.

## How we protect your Personal Information

GoSquared takes precautions — including administrative, technical and physical measures — to keep the Personal Information we hold about you accurate and proportionate, and to safeguard your Personal Information against loss, theft and misuse, as well as unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

In line with the UK's Data Protection Act 1998, we have technological and organisational measures in place to prevent unauthorised or unlawful processing of Personal Information and against accidental loss, destruction of or damage to, Personal Information.

We design our systems with high data security, availability, performance and integrity as a top priority and take precautions to keep the risk of loss, damage or corruption to a minimum. For example: We use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption, and the premises in which our physical systems are located are safeguarded by the providers of those systems. We use industry standard SSL/TLS encryption to secure data connections between your computer and our servers, as well as our servers and other servers while transmitting or exchanging sensitive or private information. Strict security mechanisms permit only authorised members of staff of GoSquared, and approved suppliers acting on our behalf, to access the systems handling and storing your Personal Information. We also employ rigorous and extensive data backup, redundancy and replication techniques.

## Registration details and updating your Personal Information

Any Personal Information entered in the fields required to register on the GoSquared platform are used strictly for the purpose of registration with GoSquared and are not passed on to any third party. We keep a record of all user information as well as preferences to create a secure and personalised service for our members, and for use with any website owned or maintained by GoSquared. Please note that a user wishing to register for the services provided by GoSquared must provide details which are accurate and correct for themselves. This means that the individual responsible for registering should only register for themselves and not on behalf of any other individual. It is also prohibited for users to have multiple accounts with GoSquared. If an individual loses a password for their account then they should use the password reset facility provided or contact GoSquared Support to recover access to their existing account rather than create a new account. This is particularly important because we do not allow users to register multiple accounts with the same e-mail address.

GoSquared has safeguards in place to keep your Personal Information accurate, complete, and up-to-date for the purposes for which it is used. Naturally, you always have the right to access and correct the Personal Information you have provided. You can help us ensure that your contact information and preferences are accurate, complete, and up-to-date by visiting www.gosquared.com. And you can request a copy of your Personal Information, your product registration history, and your interactions with our sales and support agents by contacting us via email – see further information on this below.

## Cookies and other tracking technologies on our Websites

 **What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small amount of data that often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer or mobile phone (referred to here as a "device") browser from a website and is stored on your device's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser usually only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other websites. Many websites send cookies whenever a user visits in order to track online traffic flows.

 **Our use of cookies**

When you access our Websites, we may automatically (i.e. not by registration) collect information that is not personally-identifiable (e.g. type of Internet browser and computer operating system used; domain name of the website from which you came; number of visits, average time spent, pages viewed). We may use this information to measure the use of our Websites and improve their content, and to customise your experience and provide greater convenience each time you interact with us. We also use other technologies to study traffic patterns on our Websites.

When you view our Websites we may also store certain information on your computer in the form of a cookie file. By using a cookie we are able to simplify and personalise our Websites for any subsequent visits you make. If you wish to block or erase the use of cookies then please refer to the relevant instructions in your web browser.

Here is a list of the main cookies set by our Websites, and what each is used for:

 **g535510n**  
Session cookie, allowing users to log into our website. Stores a unique session identifier.

 **gs_um**  
Used for “remember me” functionality, automatically logging in the user when they return to the site, if they have opted to do so.

 **Google Analytics**

Google analytics sets its own set of cookies to provide analytics functionality. View a list of the cookies Google Analytics sets [here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies#cookiesSet).

 **GoSquared cookies**

We use our own tracking services on our website to help us understand how visitors use the website so we can provide a better service. You can see a list of cookies the GoSquared analytics service sets in our Statement on Protecting Your Data.

 **How do you delete cookies?:** If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our Websites, or indeed any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. The Help function within your browser should tell you how. Alternatively, you may wish to visit www.aboutcookies.org which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your computer as well as more general information about cookies. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone you will need to refer to your handset manual.

Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of our Websites.

## General matters

GoSquared may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way a notice will be posted on our Websites along with the updated Privacy Policy.

The GoSquared Privacy Policy is subject to change without prior notice. By using any of our Websites you abide by the terms and conditions stated on <http://www.gosquared.com/legal/terms/> as well as this Privacy Policy.

All details contained in this Privacy Policy are correct at the time of writing.

Any feedback you provide at this site will be deemed to be non-confidential. GoSquared will be free to use such information on an unrestricted basis.

## Accessing your Personal Information

The UK's Data Protection Act 1998 (the "Act") may give you the right to access Personal Information held by us about you. This right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to identity checks, and a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the Personal Information we hold about you.

### Contact us

If you have questions or concerns about GoSquared's Privacy Policy or data processing, please contact us at our address below, or via email at [support@gosquared.com](mailto:support@gosquared.com) or call us on +44 (0) 20 8144 0401. The GoSquared Support Team will respond to your inquiry as soon as possible (usually in a few hours).

The address to write to is:

GoSquared Ltd.,  
3 Barn Hawe, High Street,  
Edenbridge,  
Kent,  
England,  
TN8 5AQ
